<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="2.4.0">Jekyll</generator>
<link href="http://ihadtendollars.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
<link href="http://ihadtendollars.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
<updated>2016-03-06T12:37:47-08:00</updated>
<id>http://ihadtendollars.com/</id>
<title>I Had Ten Dollars</title>
<entry>
<title>Julie Legault - Amino</title>
<link href="http://ihadtendollars.com/interviews/julie-legault.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Julie Legault - Amino" />
<published>2016-02-15T00:00:00-08:00</published>
<updated>2016-02-15T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
<id>http://ihadtendollars.com/interviews/julie-legault</id>
<content type="html" xml:base="http://ihadtendollars.com/interviews/julie-legault.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amino.bio/&quot;&gt;The Amino&lt;/a&gt; just might be the most ambitious project I’ve had on the site. It’s definitely the one I feel least qualified to explain, which means I’m right in its target audience. Amino is an at home DNA hacking kit that allows anyone as young as 8 to grow their own cells and give them interesting properties, and has been described as a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dezeen.com/2015/10/28/julie-legault-synthetic-biology-amino-biolab-tamagotchi-kit/&quot;&gt;“bacterial Tomagachi”&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wired.com/2015/11/aminos-cool-bio-kit-is-like-the-easy-bake-oven-of-bioreactors/&quot;&gt;“the easy-bake oven of bio-reactors”&lt;/a&gt; by the press.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talking to Julie, it’s not hard to imagine kids and adults alike making their own pigments to create art that glows in the dark or changes color based on the type of light it’s exposed to. In the future, Amino users could also change the nutritional content of their food by creating their own yeast, or produce their own scents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love the idea of something that makes science more personal while showing off how the fruits of scientific experimentation are incorporated into our lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Amino team is almost complete hand-assembling the kits promised to their &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.indiegogo.com/projects/amino-desktop-bioengineering-for-everyone#/&quot;&gt;IndieGogo&lt;/a&gt; backers and is looking to start large scale manufacturing soon. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This interview has been edited for length and clarity&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/posts/julie-legault/aminocherry2.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/julie-legault/aminocherry2.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;You started this at MIT Media Lab and I’m curious how you got the idea to make this your project.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure. Before joining the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.media.mit.edu/&quot;&gt;Media Lab&lt;/a&gt;, I was doing wearable technology. I studied goldsmithing and I was interested in how we can use traditional making, and the traditional aesthetics of jewelry, to make wearable tech more appreciated and more desirable. [After I joined the lab] I kind of lost interest in wearable tech because I’d done quite a few projects and they’d been successful, at least in museums and stuff, at bringing the aesthetics and technology together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was looking for something new and I took a class over winter break - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.swap-mit.info/microfluidics/&quot;&gt;microfluidics for synthetic biology&lt;/a&gt;. Everyone told us when you take your winter break class, take something you would never normally do, and that is definitely a class I would never normally do. So I took that, and we had a talk from a lady named &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QfLtQwiQ_7s&quot;&gt;Natalie Kuldell&lt;/a&gt; who started a &lt;a href=&quot;http://biobuilder.org/&quot;&gt;foundation&lt;/a&gt; to teach teachers how to integrate synthetic biology into their curriculum. She was talking about how you can use cells to create perfume. One of the things we did was make E. coli smell like banana, and I thought it was amazing. The fact that I could, as a non-scientist, do this in a couple of days - assemble a genetic circuit and have it actually create something for me - was just amazing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I took another few workshops. I did one with &lt;a href=&quot;https://synbiota.com&quot;&gt;Synbiota&lt;/a&gt; where we created a violet pigment that’s actually an anti-cancerous compound. And again, that took two days. And we did it in our lab director’s kitchen, eating and drinking coffee while doing genetic engineering at the same time. I thought that was really powerful. The fact that you don’t actually even need to be in a lab, and can just be in your kitchen and still do this… I was really inspired, and I was really excited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I was speaking to my other friends at MIT and they were all terrified that I could do bio-engineering. They didn’t quite understand it and were like, “Oh, bioterrorism,” and all that. So I thought that even if very future-thinking people are still afraid… it’s mostly because they’re not experienced. Some of them eventually did a work shop and once they did it they were like, “Okay, I get it.” [I thought it was] similar to how we learn with computers. Once you start programming you kind of get it, like, “Oh, okay. I can do this. I understand it. And now I understand the whole field better.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought I would be the same with genetic engineering and synthetic biology. I thought that if we get more and more people to at least have a basic understanding of it, or a quick experience with it in high school or at home, then they’ll feel more comfortable with the subject. And they can take part in the discussions about the laws and the ethics and decide if they even want it in their body. And if they don’t, that’s fine. But at least it’s their own decision. It’s not the media telling them that they’ll die or things like that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;I’m curious where you think some of that fear comes from. Is it a fear that hobbyists will make mistakes and unleash some ungodly creation? A fear of premeditated mischief?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it’s definitely both those things. There is a sense that if anyone has access to it then anyone can start making and creating these unexpected creatures, or that people with malicious intentions will use it. If you look back in history, and this is quite apparent with computers, any time there’s a new technology or science that people don’t understand, it produces fear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the eighties, people were terrified of computers. And I think it makes sense. It’s much easier to see the dangers of it, and the benefits are sometimes so mundane, but so powerful. Like insulin is kind of a mundane thing that you don’t really think about, but I don’t know how many people rely on it to survive. I think it’s more a question of not understanding what’s going on. And when it’s behind closed doors with scientists in lab coats and anything could happen and we don’t really know… I think that’s where it comes from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;The project examples you gave were just a couple of days, and I was wondering how typical that is for projects? How long will it take to do the apps the Amino ships with?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, the first thing you need to do is to grow the cells that you’re going to transform. To grow them takes 12 hours. We usually recommend doing it overnight. So you put them in in the evening and you have them in the morning.  Then you put the DNA program in. The actual transformation, like, you putting the DNA program in the cells is only a couple of hours. But once it’s in there you need to wait for the cells to grow again, so that’s another twelve hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Biology’s a little slow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then you can put it in the liquid culture, that’s when it’s in the main chamber, and have it grow and start expressing the proteins you want. In total it’s like a 36 hour experiment where you’re not doing much some of the time - you’re just watching it grow. And that’s typical in biology. You need to wait for your cells to grow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;That’s seems pretty good though. Two days is really not that long to run an experiment, I think. For some reason when I was initially reading about it I thought it would take much longer.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yeah, I think kids can still be interested after a couple of days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Yeah, how young do you think you would go for an Amino?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The youngest we’ve had that completely did the workshop and understood what they were doing were like eight and nine years old. They were good at knowing what was going on and participating in the discussion. And then we’ve had their younger siblings, like five or six years old, and they can do the experiment, but they just can’t quite understand what they’re doing, which makes sense because they’re little. In the home context, if you have a younger sibling it would be okay to have a five or six year old do it. Right now we’re going in through schools and I wouldn’t recommend below eight. Just because you need a lot of concentration to do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Could you describe your ideal outcome from somebody owning an Amino? What are you most excited about for having these things in people’s homes?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things I am personally excited about is giving non-scientists, and people who have no interest in science, the ability to create using science. So I’m really excited for people at home to be able to create their own yeast that, say, glows in the dark. And then [having them] make cakes and grow beers from it. Just having that really simple application for something that’s actually super powerful and complex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I like imagining kids having this as a Christmas present. You know, you’re so excited when you get your Christmas gifts. I remember getting a chemistry set and following the instructions for the first few and then being like, “Fuck these instructions, I’m going to make my own.” And most of the time it didn’t work out, but I’m really excited to see kids trying to create things that we haven’t told them to. And it will still be safe because we’re only providing safe chemicals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the apps we’re putting out is to create your own pigments that either glows under UV or can glow in the dark. I’m sure someone will create a pigment that we’ve never seen before or that changes color over time or something. I think that will be really cool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;The design of kit is very pleasant. I was wondering how you decided to use wood for the case. I saw some of the early prototypes had been 3d printed, and it looked like there were some aluminum versions. How did you settle on the final design for it?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That took way longer than you would expect. When I was designing it, a lot of it was, “How do we make it not scary? How do we make it friendly and enticing enough that kids want to play with it, but also adults want to have it in their home?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things we really want to do is allow people (mostly adults, probably) to create yeast for brewing and baking. [To create] yeast with added vitamins and added flavors. So it needs to fit in the home quite well. Not something you’d be ashamed of having. Something you’d be quite proud of having.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s where the wood came from - this idea of homeliness. Something that’s quite warm, both to the eye and the touch. Something that’s as far away from what you imagine a scientific experiment lab looking like, which would probably be aluminum or plastic. I think when people think of technology, they think of aluminum from their Macbooks and everything. We’re trying to change that first perception. When you see it as a wooden box, you see it as something approachable and that you don’t need a lot of skills or knowledge to use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;With something like a brewing kit, if you were to make your own yeast, what are some of the things you could do with it.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can change the flavor of it. With baking you can add different flavors to the yeast. Or you can also add different vitamin content. If you don’t eat a lot of green veggies you could make it produce vitamin K and then you have a good excuse to eat a thousand cakes. You could also do fun things like have it change colors. You could have it glow in the dark.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You could explore the bio-sensor realm of synthetic biology. It’s similar to Arduino where you have an actuator and a sensor but on a biology level. If the bacteria detects, say, heat it will change color or smell different. That might be really interesting. I don’t know how stable it would be if you were to bake it, but that’s something we’re going to explore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;I was looking at the sensor comparisons on your site, and I was wondering how you’re able to get those lab quality sensors for so much less or in such a compact form.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lab hardware is becoming so much cheaper, but it’s mostly because now almost everyone who is a hacker/maker is an engineer and they can see what it takes to make a machine run. A centrifuge, for example, is sold for thousands of dollars, but you only need a motor that spins at 9,000 RPM. You only need a computer fan motor and a little 3D printed holder for your tube.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the things we’ve done for the first version of the Amino is break open computer fans and that sort of thing to create the system. Now we have custom sensors, but those sensors are actually modeled on other technologies that are the same as what are being used in science, except they’re in our home appliances and they’re much cheaper for it. When you’re in a big lab the equipment needs to be very precise and very reliable, but when you’re doing something like Amino in the home you don’t need that level of precision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also have a really great mechanical engineer, which really helped in making things cheaper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;We’re almost out of time and I just have two more questions that I ask for every project. What was the most surprising thing you learned while making this project?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it was that so many people came together to make it happen. I used to work in speculative design: where you come up with an idea, and you make a prototype, and it goes in a museum, and you give a few talks about it, and everyone’s very proud of you but nothing happens with it. You know, you put it in your closet or it stays in a gallery. But this time it’s actually real and friends and engineers and scientists helped out. Everyone’s been very supportive. The media lab was very supportive. Yeah, that part was really amazing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;And what was the most challenging part of realizing this project.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think we’re going through it right now. It’s going to be a really boring answer, but it’s taking it from a prototype that works and turning it into a consumer product that other people can use for a long time. With our prototype, you could have used it for like two weeks and then you would have been in trouble. But this version we’re making now, you can use it for a year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yeah, that’s quite a challenge. Of course, if we had unlimited amounts of money we could do that easily and sell it to you for 1,500 dollars or thirty grand because the pumps are so expensive, but it was a finding the right balance of quality materials and durability.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
<summary>The Amino just might be the most ambitious project I’ve had on the site. It’s definitely the one I feel least qualified to explain, which means I’m right in its target audience. Amino is an at home DNA hacking kit that allows anyone as young as 8 to grow their own cells and give them interesting properties, and has been described as a “bacterial Tomagachi” and “the easy-bake oven of bio-reactors” by the press.</summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>Nicole He - True Love Tinder Robot</title>
<link href="http://ihadtendollars.com/interviews/nicole-he.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nicole He - True Love Tinder Robot" />
<published>2016-01-12T00:00:00-08:00</published>
<updated>2016-01-12T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
<id>http://ihadtendollars.com/interviews/nicole-he</id>
<content type="html" xml:base="http://ihadtendollars.com/interviews/nicole-he.html">&lt;p&gt;Nicole’s True Love bot has everything you could want in a project: romance, robots, suspense, the slightest feeling of helplessness, a single disembodied hand – everything! As Nicole says in her description of the robot, “This project explores the idea that the computer knows us better than we know ourselves, and therefore it has better authority on who we should date than we do. In a direct way, the True Love Tinder Robot makes the user confront what it feels like to let computers make intimate decisions for us.” I think it looks like a really successful project in that regard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After you read this, you should check out the Nicole’s documentation for the project. She’s set up &lt;a href=&quot;http://nicole.pizza/true-love-tinder-robot/&quot;&gt;a page&lt;/a&gt; answering some of the more common questions and showing off a video of the robot in action. You can also read her &lt;a href=&quot;http://nicole.pizza/itp/tag/tinder-robot/&quot;&gt;process blog&lt;/a&gt; to see the robot’s development unfold. It has early sketches, code, and even a breakdown of all the parts and how much they cost. I kind of wish every project was this well documented, but then I probably wouldn’t be able to keep this site up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/posts/nicole/true-love-tinder-robot.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/nicole/true-love-tinder-robot.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Who are you and what do you do for a living?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a graduate student at NYU &lt;a href=&quot;https://tisch.nyu.edu/itp&quot;&gt;ITP&lt;/a&gt;, which is like Hogwarts but with computers. I currently do nothing to make a living, which is both terrible and wonderful (mostly terrible).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Can you tell us a little bit about the True Love Tinder Robot? How did you make it, and how did you decide that this was what you wanted to work on for your ITP project?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://nicole.pizza/true-love-tinder-robot/&quot;&gt;The True Love Tinder Robot&lt;/a&gt; was a project I made for two of my classes at ITP. It’s a robot that reads your feeling as you are looking at Tinder profiles, and then decides whether or not you are attracted to that person. If you are, the creepy robot hand will physically swipe right, and if you are not, it will swipe left. It also talks to you the whole time about your involuntary choices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I woke up in the middle of the night with the idea for this robot. I decided to run with it because I thought it would make people think about how much we trust computers with intimate decisions, and also because I thought it would be a funny project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;How did you decide the robot should talk?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was important to me that the robot express its personality. Doing this visually by showing another screen was out of the question, since the user should be focused on looking at the Tinder profiles. So it made sense to make the robot speak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way it talks to you is a big part of the experience, because it makes you feel like it’s a little bit judgmental about what’s going on. But it has the right to be, because it knows better than you. All of this adds to the question of how much we want to trust a computer with something so personal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;How does the bot decide if it’s love?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It measures galvanic skin response, which is essentially how sweaty your palms get and how that changes over time. When we are excited or nervous (the familiar feelings of love!), our palms get just a little bit sweatier. Using an Arduino, the robot can then read how the electrical conductivity of your skin changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The True Love Tinder Robot knows better than you because it knows how you &lt;em&gt;truly&lt;/em&gt; feel when you look at a person, and therefore you aren’t swiping based on how you &lt;em&gt;think&lt;/em&gt; you feel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;If it’s sweaty palms, does the bot start matching you up more over time? Do we look like we’re getting more desperate to the True Love Robot?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not necessarily - it measures the &lt;em&gt;change&lt;/em&gt; in how sweaty your palms get, so if you have naturally sweaty hands, it doesn’t mean that you’ll swipe right more. It depends on how your body reacts to each individual Tinder profile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But yes, the robot may judge you if you’re swiping right a lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;How have people generally been reacting to it?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s been a surprising flurry of response to the robot! I think it activates people’s anxieties about internet dating, biometric devices, and our own intimate relationships with computers. The people that have actually gotten to try the robot find it a little sassy, I think. But of course, it’s because the robot knows best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;What was the biggest challenge making it?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The physical fabrication was the most difficult part for me, because I have no experience in that area, and like a dumb person I did not take a class on it this semester. Drilling holes is scary for me!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;What was the “easiest” part?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess since my unconscious mind came up with the idea while I was sleeping, that was the easiest part.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;What was the most surprising thing you learned?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was surprised at how much of a reaction there has been to this project across the web and in the news, but I think people pretty much will eat up anything based around Tinder. Also, this may be cheesy, but I learned that I could come up with an original idea for something that I find interesting, and then code it and build it myself. That was pretty nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;What’s the most intimate decision you’ve let a computer decide?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This, my friend, is a secret between me and my computer.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
<summary>Nicole’s True Love bot has everything you could want in a project: romance, robots, suspense, the slightest feeling of helplessness, a single disembodied hand – everything! As Nicole says in her description of the robot, “This project explores the idea that the computer knows us better than we know ourselves, and therefore it has better authority on who we should date than we do. In a direct way, the True Love Tinder Robot makes the user confront what it feels like to let computers make intimate decisions for us.” I think it looks like a really successful project in that regard.</summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>PJ Vogt - Reply All</title>
<link href="http://ihadtendollars.com/interviews/pj-vogt.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="PJ Vogt - Reply All" />
<published>2015-05-14T00:00:00-07:00</published>
<updated>2015-05-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
<id>http://ihadtendollars.com/interviews/pj-vogt</id>
<content type="html" xml:base="http://ihadtendollars.com/interviews/pj-vogt.html">&lt;p&gt;“Okay, this is a cursed interview.” That’s the first thing I heard when I turned on the tape of interview with PJ Vogt, who co-hosts a podcast about the internet called &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/agoldmund&quot;&gt;Reply All&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/agoldmund&quot;&gt;Alex Goldman&lt;/a&gt;. He’s not wrong. Between last minute scheduling conflicts, me &lt;em&gt;losing&lt;/em&gt; close to an hour’s worth of our conversation to a bad microphone, and more dropped calls than seems plausible given all the ads about network coverage I’ve seen recently, I count myself really lucky to have what you’re reading right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reply All is basically my ideal podcast. It’s the podcast I would make if I had the skill to recognize the bones of a story well enough to pare down hours of tape into fifteen or twenty minutes of narrative, the attention to detail required to make it sound professional, and the empathy it takes to get someone to open up about their most personal moments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The show has always managed to find interesting topics and report on them incredibly well. I was particularly impressed by this early episode on &lt;a href=&quot;http://gimletmedia.com/episode/9-yik-yak/&quot;&gt;Yik Yak, racism, and Colgate University&lt;/a&gt;. Even when I think I already know the story, like when &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/chiaraatik&quot;&gt;Chiara Atik&lt;/a&gt; followed along with &lt;a href=&quot;http://gimletmedia.com/episode/4-follow-the-money/&quot;&gt;someone’s breakup via Venmo&lt;/a&gt; the show manages to add a lot to my sense of the people involved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine you’ve just read about a young PJ interning at NPR and deciding to stay there instead of returning to school. Imagine he’s talked about looking for stories where the subject shows personal growth. Imagine he’s said nice things about working with Alex. Now read the rest of the interview, please.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Why do you think people share the things they do with you? On some episodes you’ve even kind of told them that if you were in their position you don’t think you would go on the show.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, Alex has said that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t know. When someone’s doing it, a lot of times it’ll feel very lucky and it feels like a fragile thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alex and I both worked in public radio, and public radio is a weird thing. But you think of it as a normal thing. It’s like, “Why would you tell a bunch of strangers something?” “Oh, it’s for NPR.” And somehow that makes sense. But, like, “Why would you tell a bunch of strangers something?” “Oh, it’s for an internet culture podcast…” I don’t know why people do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it’s one way to construct meaning out of life. Something awful, or astounding, or embarrassing happens, and the act of telling it and being listened to and having somebody try to understand it [creates meaning].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think a lot of people who like listening to things like that, who like listening to stories and interviews, they’re kind of waiting for the day where someone’s going to sit down with them and just talk to them and just [say], “Let me know what happened to you.” I think maybe that’s part of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that’s some of the instinct that makes me want to do this kind of thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Part of it seems like maybe they want to build their own understanding of it, but do you think that there’s also this hunger for you to build a narrative around it? To see how somebody else takes their story and finds something meaningful in it?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yeah, and I think that that can be frustrating for people. I always worry when we profile somebody how they’re going to feel about how we see their life. But, beyond the vulnerability of that, I think there is something nice about just, like, “If somebody else were paying very careful attention to the things that I’m going through, and trying very hard to understand me, what would they come away with?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that can be valuable for people. I mean, sometimes it’s weird. Sometimes you’ll do an interview with somebody and you’ll talk to them for two or three or four hours. And you’re talking about big stuff. You’re talking about something that happened to them that was a big enough deal that it’s a story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a really quick and intimate thing. And one of the strange things is that then you’re done. You spend a bunch more time alone with their voice, thinking about them and writing about them. And then the episode goes up and you shoot them an email like, “Hey, just so you know, it’s up.” And, usually, they say that they liked it. And that’s it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s very strange. It feels like there should be another thing that happens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;So, most of the time when they say they liked it, do they expand on that? Is it usually a pretty perfunctory e-mail back? Or is it like, “I think I think you really got this right,” or, “I hadn’t seen it that way but now I think that makes sense”?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usually, it’s a little bit longer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you don’t hear anything. I haven’t had the experience yet of somebody being like, “You really got this wrong,” or, “You really mischaracterized me.” Yeah, it’s usually like a medium-length email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s nice. It’s also weird because a lot of times it’s like they’ve said everything they can. Because, the way we interview, we spend a long time with people. You get to a point where they have nothing more to say about the thing. You really just, you know, relentlessly made them talk about it. And then you’ve put every good idea you have about it into the piece, hopefully.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we were at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.onthemedia.org/blogs/on-the-media/&quot;&gt;TLDR&lt;/a&gt; I did a profile of this songwriter who was amazing, and he does a newsletter called &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.moternmedia.com/home.html&quot;&gt;The Long Walks Newsletter.&lt;/a&gt; It’s almost like a zine, and it’s just walks he’s gone on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s really nice. It’s kind of what you wish you got with other people, which is continuing glimpses into how they are afterwards. We actually probably could check back in on people sometimes. It’s one of the things a podcast can do that a radio show doesn’t do because it can’t, and you kind of don’t realize it’s an option because you’re still used to being a radio show.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Why is it something a podcast can do but a radio show can’t do?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think with a podcast it’s easier to refer back to something you did before. You can do it sometimes [on a radio show]. Serial could make episodes that were built on the assumption that people would start from the beginning. But it’s harder for This American Life to be like, “This week on This American Life we’re going to do chapter ten in a story that we started two months ago, and if you’d like to start from the beginning you have to go back in time.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;That makes sense.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;When you’re constructing a story, after after the interview – and you’ve talked about not being able to get what you need sometimes for a story – as you edit it together, how much of the meaning do you feel like you and Alex are kind of like imbuing it with?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s a tricky question. I mean, I think what we try to do is we take the interview we have. We talk about what we think it means, but we make sure that we’re talking to the people in the story about what we think it means, also.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the worst case scenario would be [that] you tell somebody’s story and you have some fancy, highfalutin idea about what it all meant and they would think it was total bullshit. Like, it’s &lt;em&gt;okay&lt;/em&gt; if they think it’s total bullshit, but you need to give them the chance to tell you that they think it’s total bullshit. And you want to give them that chance in tape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel like it’s important to get as close to the truth as you can. I think if you have the experience of somebody doing a story about you then you look at media differently afterwards, because you just sort of see how they get it wrong. Even if [they] don’t get the facts wrong, just like how they kind of miss it. Ideally, the people that we talk to would feel that as little as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Yeah, I was thinking about cases where you have to interpret motivation for things, and people are really bad about understanding their own motivations for stuff.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yeah, in that case you just say, “Can I test out my theory on why you do what you do?” I mean, we did in &lt;a href=&quot;http://gimletmedia.com/episode/16-why-is-mason-reese-crying/&quot;&gt;this episode that came out last night.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/j_goldstein&quot;&gt;Jonathan Goldstein&lt;/a&gt; reported this story for us about a former child star named Mason Reese who was uploading all these old videos of himself on TV onto YouTube.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But one of the videos was of him breaking down crying on a talk show when he was seven. Jonathan really wanted to know why that had happened, and he had all these theories about why. He tried them out on him, and Mason was just like, “Nope. Nope. Nope,” which is kind of the good thing about radio. The person’s perspective is, by default, kind of going to be included more because everything has to happen in tape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, it was sort of nice. [Jonathan]’s trying to guess his motivations. And it felt like he stayed with him until he got a reasonable theory about what they might have been.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;And, also, sometimes I guess just hearing a person say “No” and their hesitation as they mull it over can help a lot too for the listener making up their own mind.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yeah, and what’s nice about radio is there’s room for that ambiguity. Like, if that happened in print you’d say, “They said, ‘No,’ but then there was a considered pause.” You’re kind of forcing your perspective a little bit harder. I think our perspective is pretty strongly in our pieces, but there’s at least a little bit of room to say, “Here’s what I saw, and here’s what I thought about it; but [you], the listener, can make up your own mind about what [you’re] hearing.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like pieces like that. I’m trying to learn how to let the tape talk more and me talk a little bit less.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;You just mentioned that you guys have a strong perspective. Sometimes the episodes seem to end with a lesson or a moral that kind of wraps it up. Is that something you think about and try to do, or is it that sometimes they just seem obvious?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;I remember the episode with the guy who does &lt;a href=&quot;http://gimletmedia.com/episode/14-the-art-of-making-and-fixing-mistakes/&quot;&gt;all the Wikipedia edits&lt;/a&gt;, and you guys kind of come in and say, like, “It’s easy to make this assumption about this guy, or have this image of him, but keep this in mind.” I forget exactly how it ended, but it seemed like that was one where you guys tried to put a lesson at the end of it.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think where it comes out of is, usually, the thing that makes me want to do a story is that we’ve got a question about it. It’s interesting that this person is doing this thing, but what makes us want to do a story is knowing why they do it. That big piece of writing, or sometimes it’s a big piece of tape, but the thing at the end where it’s like, “and this is what it all meant,” I think that’s us trying to work it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, a lot of that was I wanted to know why he did it. I wanted to know what he felt about it. But also, I’m not a person whose instincts run towards correction. Like, I’m not a grammar person. I’m not a precise person. I like trying to understand the perspective of the people that we’re profiling. And so, for me, I think some of the writing was me trying to put myself in his shoes from my shoes to be like, “There’s a part of me that can not stand this kind of behavior, but if you talk to him long enough it’s very understandable. And I can kind of see how somebody like him would see somebody like me.” So, sometimes that writing is like, “We went into this with a question, and here’s what we think the answer is at this point.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Do you think that the show has helped you make sense of the internet and how people interact and stuff?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;It seems like that’s kind of the biggest overarching question: “How does technology affect the way that we interact with each other and find meaning and friendship?” You know, there are all these petty things, but also all this room room for all these small, great moments. Do you think that you have a better handle on that now from doing the show?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel like doing the show forces us to learn a lot, and [learn] quickly, about technology. Both in the mechanical sense – “There’s a new thing, what does it do?” – and also the larger questions about how we feel about all the various ways the internet is making us feel as a culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I’ll look back at our episodes and I’ll see that the topics we were picking, or the stories we were choosing, or the way we were covering the stories, really reflected stuff we were working on as humans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s funny because it’s a show about people, but it’s not a confessional show by any stretch. But you’ll see that you sure wanted to ask people about falling in love at that point. You really wanted to ask people about taking a risk, or having anxiety about work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’d think doing a show about one thing would feel limiting, and maybe one day it will, but it’s strange how much of non-internet life actually ends up getting filtered into talking about the internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Yeah, it seems like since we do everything on it now it’s like a lens for all action, kind of. Like, I lost a friend recently, and I was listening to the episode where the guy was looking for information about &lt;a href=&quot;http://gimletmedia.com/episode/11-did-errol-morris-brother-invent-email/&quot;&gt;his brother inventing email.&lt;/a&gt; That was super relevant to me just because of the idea of all this mystery around other people and how much of somebody’s life goes on outside of your perception. They could be a completely different person, or have sides of themselves that you never really imagined, or problems much deeper than you knew.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;I think it’s impossible for that not to come out in a technology show. As long as there are people around, human problems find their way in.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yeah, some technology reporting, I think more like the mainstream than in the nerdier stuff that we tend to consume, will be like, “Is Twitter making us lonely?” “Is ‘Some Service’ making us hornier?” Obviously, we are who we are, and when someone dies we miss them and wonder about them. And it just sort of gives us these different places to act out the human things we were going to do anyway, but maybe those things are like a little bit changed, or a little bit heightened because of the tools we’ve been given. I think that stays interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of what people do on the internet, because a lot of it’s private, they think it’s weirder than it is. One of the nice things about doing this sort of reporting is you’re like, “No, no. Pretty much everyone’s doing a version of this.” It’s nice to be able to talk about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Have you ever been the subject of a show like yours?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been interviewed, but I’ve never had somebody spend a bunch of time with me and then write down how my life looked to them.  I don’t know if I’d be great at it. I think it would be really hard for me to relax and not try to kind of manage it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Like not try to edit it yourself for them?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exactly. Like, you have this story you kind of want them to walk away with. Also, I talk too much. I would end up saying something that I wouldn’t want in there. Ooof, it would be an uncomfortable thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alex would be a lot better at it. He’s just, I think, a more functional person in that kind of environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;If you had to pick what you thought someone would come to you with like, “I think this is like a representative moment, rich for interpretation about you,” what do you think it would be?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, last night we were crashing on the episode and we were in a studio that John Delore, [Gimlet’s] technical director, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mlieber&quot;&gt;Matt Lieber&lt;/a&gt;, [Gimlet’s] co-founder, built. It’s just, like, a white box in a warehouse. It’s almost like a shipping container. It’s nicer than a shipping container, but it &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; a lot like a shipping container. There were five or six of us at one point, and a dog, crammed into this box just listening very closely to the episode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By Wednesday night the kinds of edits you’re making are like, “I think this silence is a millisecond too long, and I think that clip needs to come up a half second faster, and I think we should change this word to that word.” I sort of felt like if you wanted to understand our show, that was the room to understand it in. The suggestions people were making, and the way that they were with each other – I think if you were trying to write this place, and if you were trying to write our show, the way to understand it would be in that room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But somebody could write that I was, like, a shitty tyrant or a whiny baby. I don’t know what somebody would go into that room and come out with, but I would be terrified whatever it was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like, I don’t think, “shitty tyrant,” but maybe, “whiny baby.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;They come out and they’re just like, “Why won’t he meet Alex’s baby?!”&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hahahah, that baby lives in New Jersey!&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
<summary>“Okay, this is a cursed interview.” That’s the first thing I heard when I turned on the tape of interview with PJ Vogt, who co-hosts a podcast about the internet called Reply All with Alex Goldman. He’s not wrong. Between last minute scheduling conflicts, me losing close to an hour’s worth of our conversation to a bad microphone, and more dropped calls than seems plausible given all the ads about network coverage I’ve seen recently, I count myself really lucky to have what you’re reading right now.</summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>Amanda Hess - Users</title>
<link href="http://ihadtendollars.com/interviews/amanda-hess.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Amanda Hess - Users" />
<published>2015-04-24T00:00:00-07:00</published>
<updated>2015-04-24T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
<id>http://ihadtendollars.com/interviews/amanda-hess</id>
<content type="html" xml:base="http://ihadtendollars.com/interviews/amanda-hess.html">&lt;p&gt;With this interview I’m taking a bit of a departure from the site’s premise since Amanda’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.slate.com/articles/technology/users.html&quot;&gt;new column at Slate&lt;/a&gt; is her real job. Who cares though, because Amanda is great!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amanda has been covering serious issues with great care for years, and I’m always impressed by how well researched and sourced her articles are. When I heard that she had a new column centered on the internet I was really curious about how she would approach it, and knew I had to talk to her about it for the site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Okay, so I want to ask you about your new column, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.slate.com/articles/technology/users.html&quot;&gt;Users&lt;/a&gt;. First, how does having a column work? Is this your main thing now? How much time do you devote to this, and how much time do you spend writing other things outside of the column?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s all really new to me also. I was freelancing for a long time, and I was freelancing mostly for Slate. Then I got a full time job at Slate and I started freelancing other places less, but still doing it. Now, I have my job at Slate and I’m also contributing to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/section/magazine?action=click&amp;amp;contentCollection=Magazine&amp;amp;region=TopBar&amp;amp;module=HomePage-Title&amp;amp;pgtype=article&quot;&gt;New York Times Magazine&lt;/a&gt; infrequently over the year. That will probably be the extent of the freelancing that I do this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;And then within Slate is everything you do going to fall under this Users category, or are you still going to be doing &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.slate.com/blogs/xx_factor.html&quot;&gt;XX Factor&lt;/a&gt; and stuff like that?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At least for now, I’m trying for it all to be Users, because it’s so natural and easy for me to have a take about feminism and women. I’m trying not to do it, like at all, for a while at least. Maybe I’ll circle back to it later, but I’m trying to force myself to have ideas about the internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;That’s interesting because part of my next question was how you ended up moving to Users; but, just watching your work, I kind of assumed that that it was a progression from XX Factor being really broad to you exploring women on the internet, and women’s experiences on the internet, and starting the transition that way. Is that right?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Umm, no.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mean, sort of. It was a lot more specific than that. It was actually an idea that was conceived of by my editors as something that they wanted more coverage of. And it was pretty obvious that I’d gotten kind of tired of writing about women all the time. But I think you’re right. Like, if you’ve read any of the things I’ve written in this category, a lot of them could have been written for Double X because they have some gender component to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like, the first thing I wrote was about why suicide prevention online doesn’t adequately reach young men. It’s funny because that’s very much a story about gender, but it wouldn’t really work that well in Double X because Double X is about women even though it’s usually about, sort of, gender more widely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What else have I written that’s sort of gender-y? Oh, I wrote something about the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.slate.com/articles/technology/users/2015/04/eggplant_rising_how_the_purple_fruit_surpassed_the_banana_as_the_most_phallic.html&quot;&gt;eggplant emoji&lt;/a&gt; that’s about sex on the internet, which is something that I’ve written about for a while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I think they saw this opportunity for me to do something that I had been doing for a while, but that was a little bit of a departure from it too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;That’s interesting. I guess I kind of saw the emoji one as having to do with sex, but I also thought of it as being really similar, conceptually, to the thing you wrote about how, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2015/03/01/magazine/when-did-youre-welcome-become-a-gloat.html?smid=tw-nytmag&amp;amp;_r=0&quot;&gt;“You’re welcome,”&lt;/a&gt; became super snarky because it was kind of about the evolution of language. It’s just that one evolved before the internet, and one evolved after.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yeah, and that one ended up being about women too. [laughs] This is actually one of the reasons that I was not really interested in writing dedicatedly about feminism anymore, or women, or whatever it was that I was writing about before. I think it’s really interesting and important for people to write about that stuff off the lady pages. You know what I mean?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Off the what pages?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Off the “lady pages.” Not for a female-specific audience. But, also, much of the reason I’ve been writing about that is because I’m so used to seeing things in that way. So that’s where my analysis tends to go, and it’s something I’m really trying to to work on. To expand it. But a lot of times if I need to have an interesting idea about something on the internet there’s going to be some gender component to it. For now at least&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Given that, where do you see Users fitting in in overall tech reporting, or even just Slate’s tech or internet culture pieces? Have you kind of identified a space that you want to carve out for yourself?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s a great question. So, I don’t… I’m trying to figure out things that I &lt;em&gt;don’t&lt;/em&gt; write about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Sometimes that’s the easiest way. You can see something and be like, “I wouldn’t cover that,” to get down to it.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I actually didn’t come up with this name - I’m trying to remember who at Slate came up this name, “Users.” I think it might have been &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/juliaturner&quot;&gt;Julia Turner&lt;/a&gt;, our editor in chief. But, it’s actually been really useful, because I’m trying to focus on how people actually use the internet; as opposed to, like, people who are creating the spaces on the internet, or the culture of Silicon Valley or something. I don’t write about that stuff. And I don’t write about, like, new phones or anything like that. Unless a new phone is creating a crazy new way that people have relationships with each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Are you going to cover that heartbeat thing in the Apple watch?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Umm… no. Probably not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, there are a lot of places that sort of do both of those things. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dailydot.com/&quot;&gt;The Daily Dot&lt;/a&gt; does those things really well, and also writes about, you know, strange things that are happening on the internet. One of the challenges that I’ve personally found in writing about this stuff is, like, writing about internet controversies. Or, like, weird places on the internet that resonate beyond themselves in some way. So it’s not just like, “weird people doing weird stuff,” or weird obsessions. [Things] that say something about how the world is changing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Do you have any favorite niche spaces right now? Anything that’s really interesting to you, or that you think is home to something new, or you can’t stop looking at?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s a good question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t think - yet - that anything I’ve written about has come from me being actually personally interested in anything, or being drawn to a part of the internet, with the probable exception of the story that I wrote about &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.slate.com/articles/technology/users/2015/03/zayn_malik_quits_one_direction_directioner_conspiracy_theories_bloom_online.html&quot;&gt;One Direction conspiracy theories.&lt;/a&gt; Which is, like, a personal interest of mine. It tends to come about from just talking to people. Like, I’ll find a person - and usually it’s someone who I know who is plugged into the internet in some way that I’m not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like this guy, this wonderful guy, emailed me a few months ago, right after I had started doing this [column]. He emailed me to say that he liked my work, but that something I had written about gamergate he thought I had gotten it wrong. I had, like, misinterpreted the motivations of gamergate people. Usually, I would not respond to that email. But because I was just starting this thing I was like, “I am definitely responding to this e-mail and seeing what this guy knows about gamergate that I don’t.” And and it turns out the answer is, “a lot.” But at some point I had a conversation with him that was like, “So, even though I really appreciate you laying this out for me, I’m not interested in writing about gamergate. I find it really boring. But, maybe there are some other things that you are paying attention to on the internet that would be interesting for me. So, he’s become a really good source, just, pointing out some places where he hangs out. I’m still trying to get to that point of what they mean about, you know, humanity or whatever, but he’s been a really good source.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I’m also just cravenly asking anyone if they know teenagers who will email me and tell me what they do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;I always thought you were pretty plugged into that teen beat.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, I’m like twenty-nine now. You know, I keep getting older and teenagers stay the same age. People who I might have talked to who were seventeen a few years ago aren’t teenagers anymore. They can be a good bridge to younger people, but you really have to keep getting new sources if you write about teenagers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;I forgot about that. So, do you think you’re going to become the type of person that spends a lot of time in these niche sites, or is it mostly, like, an academic interest to you where people will direct you to them and you’ll look at them enough to write a story but you won’t spend a whole lot of time crawling through these communities? Or trying every new app that comes out to see what’s happening on it?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right, or will I become a part of them? Will I become so interested in the community that I become part of it? I don’t think so. I have to say that I’m not a super social person, in general.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have my friends who I gchat. And I have my co-workers who I Slack with. And I have my boyfriend who I text. [But,] I don’t have a big… You pointed this out. Like, I just tweet less and less. So, I don’t think that I have the same relationship with internet communities as like a lot of people that I end up writing about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for the app stuff, it’s really hard. I don’t know how, but somehow all the P.R. people instantly figured out that I was writing about the internet now; so, every new app that comes out, I get a pitch about. And it’s, like, for the first time in my life my phone is full and I have to start deleting apps. It’s hard to know what to even spend time on because there are so many of them. Like, I got this pitch from this woman the other day who – And they have their little packet how to make it not about the app, but it makes no sense. She was like, “I have this guy who wants to talk about how emojis are too limited, and they’re going to limit our, you know, emotional capabilities in conversation.” But, he really made his app where you can, like, put graffiti on photos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, it doesn’t really make sense, but, also, he designed &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/koi-pond/id286420263?mt=8&quot;&gt;Koi Pond&lt;/a&gt;, which is one of my favorite apps. It’s, like, for relaxation. This is showing you how old I am; because, I don’t want the graffiti app, I want the relaxation app. There are fish swimming in a pond, and you can move little things and it makes little rippling water noises and the fish scatter. And they slowly come back. I’m sort of interested in that space, so I might end up interviewing him sometime in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;[At this point I started talking about &lt;a href=&quot;http://motherboard.vice.com/read/this-adorable-japanese-cat-game-is-everywhere-and-we-tried-to-figure-it-out&quot;&gt;that cat app&lt;/a&gt;, and I’ve decided to spare you all from having to read about how I can’t make my cats happy.]&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;For that stuff, it seems like you would kind of wait until something’s mature enough, and then you’ll hear about people are using it in kind of a new way. You don’t really want to cover a brand new app, right? Like, you to see how people have kind of incorporated it into their lives.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unless, I mean, so the idea of having a column, I guess, is that it’s about you having an idea about something. So, I guess I can see… maybe inspiration will strike with something new, but it hasn’t happened yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Oh yeah, since it’s a column, how often do you have to write it? I’ve heard some criticism of columns from a few people that the rate you have to produce it just ensures that you’re going to be at some point like, “Oh God, I just need anything!” And it sets you up for embarrassing retrospectives later.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yeah, like I’ll write something offensive? Yeah, uhhh, I don’t know. I mean, it’s interesting; because, when I was doing the Double X stuff, there were some times when I was just blogging where I was like, “Here’s a video that is gender related.” But there’s actually not a lot of news in the “woman space,” you know? So, everything that I was writing was something that had some kind of take on it. And sometimes it wasn’t even new. And sometimes, like, it was bad. And sometimes it wasn’t bad. And I think the fast pace sort of forced me to do some things I wouldn’t have done otherwise that ended up being good. And, also, the opposite happened sometimes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things that I’m hoping to be better at as a person - as a journalist – is things that are longer than the column length. So, like, a feature length thing, I think is more difficult for me to wrap my mind around about what ideas should be that length and have that amount of investment in them. I’m hoping to figure that out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;One thing I feel kind of comes through in some of your posts, I guess in general and from Users, is that technology is kind of letting us work through things that we’ve always had to work through, but a little bit more publicly. Or, at least maybe more observably. I don’t know if it’s right to say it’s public if it’s anonymous or semi-anonymous.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;How do you think that technology has helped make behaviors and urges more visible?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s a really difficult question. I tend to agree with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.washingtoncitypaper.com/blogs/sexist/author/ahess/&quot;&gt;Nathan Jurgensen&lt;/a&gt;. Do you know who he is? He’s a sociologist who writes about the internet, and he has promoted this idea
called “digital dualism” which [debunks] the idea that online and offline lives are separate things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s difficult to believe that, as I do, and also think that there’s anything new and interesting in writing about different technologies. And some people, I think, do that really well. And I don’t think I’m really one of those people. So the things that I often end up writing about – that are about the culture of the internet – they don’t really… They don’t tend to interact much with how it’s different than it used to be. Do you know what I mean?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s more like – and this is not something I’ve actually thought about, but I’m articulating just now – it’s more like reporting on the internet like it’s a place. And it doesn’t tend to really specifically have a commentary or a critique about how it’s different from before we had the internet or how it’s different when we’re not on the internet much at all. I guess. Maybe I’m wrong. Am I wrong?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;I don’t think so. I mean, it’s an interesting question. It kind of comes up in the piece about &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.slate.com/articles/technology/users/2015/03/lacey_spears_might_have_had_munchausen_by_proxy_by_internet_are_internet.html&quot;&gt;diagnosing mental disorders&lt;/a&gt; and whether internet [disorders] are different or do they just allow us different manifestations of existing problems? One thing is it seems like things happen faster on the internet because we always have access to it. Is the fact that behaviors are accelerated novel or not? Maybe that’s a significant question?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yeah. I think you’re right, and I don’t know. That’s a good example of a thing that I wrote about, “whether disorders are different online.” Because that’s like a classic Amanda Hess thing where, like, I don’t say whether they are or not, and I don’t know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t know if they’re different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know that one guy thinks they are and one guy thinks they’re not, really. But I have no idea if we should see them as different things. But, I do agree with you that it’s a really interesting question. I’m probably not going to answer it. But hopefully I can illuminate the question in some way. That’s usually my goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;I think that makes sense. I think that’s kind of like the best anybody can do a lot of the time.&lt;/h4&gt;

</content>
<summary>With this interview I’m taking a bit of a departure from the site’s premise since Amanda’s new column at Slate is her real job. Who cares though, because Amanda is great!</summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>Joanne McNeil - Emotional Labor Extension</title>
<link href="http://ihadtendollars.com/interviews/joanne-mcneil.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Joanne McNeil - Emotional Labor Extension" />
<published>2015-03-21T00:00:00-07:00</published>
<updated>2015-03-21T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
<id>http://ihadtendollars.com/interviews/joanne-mcneil</id>
<content type="html" xml:base="http://ihadtendollars.com/interviews/joanne-mcneil.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jomc&quot;&gt;Joanne McNeil&lt;/a&gt;’s Emotional Labor Extension is a bit different than the projects I normally post about here because it’s already well documented. She wrote a &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/message/canned-email-eb6f4ba843d9&quot;&gt;fantastic post about it&lt;/a&gt; that resonated with me, and I think will resonate with anyone who sends email even semi-regularly. Reading about her anxiety sending personal emails and trying to compensate for the form’s limitations in expression I was reminded of the time a coworker put five exclamation points in a reply-all email to our CEO and a collegue stopped by her desk and said, “Dang, you sounded maaaad.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also know the feeling of disappointment and worry that comes from looking at a paltry line or two in gmail’s “compose” window, wondering why my letter looks so bad. I was having such a hard time with the disconnect between how terrible my emails sounded to my ears and how much I felt for their recipients that I actually started a concerted effort to improve my letter writing with my friend Ryan (of &lt;a href=&quot;http://ihadtendollars.com/interviews/ryan-wolf.html&quot;&gt;Is Ryan At The Office&lt;/a&gt; fame) where we vowed to write substantial letters to one another. I found writing decent letters in an age of ubiquitious access (including being able to check whether someone is at their office whenever I felt like it) that I proposed we both buy and read a collection of letters between Paul Auster and J.M. Coetzee so we could have something to fall back on for discussion that we weren’t talking about anywhere else. I think it helped, and I ended up really valuing those letters, but I still feel like my emails end up being staid and mechanical far too often.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joanne’s Emotional Labor Extension is a great project because it takes a problem we’re so familiar with that it’s just become a part of daily life, and makes it novel again so we can look at it with fresh eyes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, Joanne, now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Who are you and what do you do for a living?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.joannemcneil.com/essays/&quot;&gt;writer&lt;/a&gt; and most of my essays appear on Medium’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/message/&quot;&gt;The Message&lt;/a&gt; I just completed a residency at Eyebeam in NYC, where I worked on this project and hosted a series of events called &lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/eyebeamnyc/sets/new-topics-in-social-computing&quot;&gt;New Topics in Social Computing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;What is the Emotional Labor email extension?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/gmail-emotional-labor/foonnlnklmnakfifejjjfhchclfkgkgh&quot;&gt;Chrome extension that works for Gmail&lt;/a&gt;. It adds a friendly greeting, changes periods for multiple exclamation marks and swaps out words like “organization” “schedule” and “work” with things like “jk” or “much love.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I began testing it on famous emails that likely were sent or received through Gmail. So the first examples were on an email from Keith Alexander to Eric Schmidt, an email from Schmidt to Steve Jobs, and the “God’sApstls” threat to Sony executives. A &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/eyebeam/16419413486/&quot;&gt;video of these emails&lt;/a&gt; before-and-after using the Emotional Labor extension played in the Eyebeam Annual Showcase exhibition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Can you describe the logic behind how the extension punches up the emails? Does every period turn into exclamation points? How does it decide where to insert smiley faces?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every comma is replaced with a period and a smiley face follows that. That makes some sentences choppy and nonsensical. Oh well. The text that is swapped in is greeting card treacly like “dear heart” and “hearts and stars.” And yes, every period turns to three exclamation marks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made it look fake because otherwise I might start using it. It’s too tempting to have this extension that opens up demurely “I hope you are doing well. Excited to hear more about your projects! [blah blah…]”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/posts/joanne/emotional-labor.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;313&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/joanne/emotional-labor.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;You wrote that you made it this way to draw attention to the fact that you find this type of interaction exhausting. Did you find that making the extension helped? Was posting about it and getting your frustrations on the record cathartic at all?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I will search my inbox for sentences like “I’ve been thinking of you” and cringe at the number of botched attempts at persuasion, flirtation, and/or forced kindness in what is now over ten years of messages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I was thinking about this when a good friend’s wife was in the hospital and I was trying hard to send an email with positive vibes without leaning on weak tea sympathy cliches like “you’re in my thoughts.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s no word like “tongue-tied” when it comes to email, but it is a pretty common predicament. In person, you can smile a certain way, or you can laugh or cry with someone. This project helped me communicate some of my frustration with the limits to language over the internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;What was making it like? Were you trying to do anything for the first time in order to make it, and did you learn anything that surprised you?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not much of a coder and I thought the extension would be much harder to build than it actually was, so the biggest surprise was that I could do it. Well, with help. I mentioned my idea for the project to &lt;a href=&quot;http://lauren-mccarthy.com/&quot;&gt;Lauren McCarthy&lt;/a&gt; and she invited me to her &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.creativeapplications.net/reviews/appropriating-interaction-technologies-social-hacking-at-itp/&quot;&gt;Appropriating Interaction Technologies&lt;/a&gt; class at ITP with &lt;a href=&quot;http://kylemcdonald.net/&quot;&gt;Kyle McDonald&lt;/a&gt;. The code began as a quick case study in their class on browser extensions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a few ideas related to the project and will keep experimenting with it. Right now, I’m learning more about Markov text generators and other ways to automate language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;You mention that, “What was once the concern of professional writers is now a burden we all share, as we communicate all day long over email and texts.” But correspondence has been a part of normal life &lt;a href=&quot;http://geekologie.com/2015/02/poor-service-has-existed-forever-tablet.php&quot;&gt;for a long time.&lt;/a&gt; Do you think the simple availability of our partners, or the ease of response, has made it harder to compose a longer message? Do you think the form of a “letter” has a place in our daily lives anymore?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Probably my level of comfort with someone is revealed in the informality of an email — lowercase letters, run-on sentences, weird mixed metaphors, etc. But the letter still has a place in my life. I’m lucky to have people in my life who put great care into it. I find that kind of writing much easier and that it comes more naturally than the kind of stuffy formality with professional contacts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Since you made the extension, have your letters come under greater scrutiny from your pen pals and colleagues?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a week, I was even more anxious about sounding nice than normally. But since then, I’ve dropped a lot of affectations. I am guessing people now cut me a lot more slack after creating a project/writing an essay about how much emotional work goes into trying hard to not offend people over email.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
<summary>Joanne McNeil’s Emotional Labor Extension is a bit different than the projects I normally post about here because it’s already well documented. She wrote a fantastic post about it that resonated with me, and I think will resonate with anyone who sends email even semi-regularly. Reading about her anxiety sending personal emails and trying to compensate for the form’s limitations in expression I was reminded of the time a coworker put five exclamation points in a reply-all email to our CEO and a collegue stopped by her desk and said, “Dang, you sounded maaaad.”</summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>Katie Rose Pipkin &amp;amp; Loren Schmidt - infloresence.city</title>
<link href="http://ihadtendollars.com/interviews/katie-rose-pipkin-and-loren-schmidt.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Katie Rose Pipkin &amp; Loren Schmidt - infloresence.city" />
<published>2015-02-26T00:00:00-08:00</published>
<updated>2015-02-26T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
<id>http://ihadtendollars.com/interviews/katie-rose-pipkin-and-loren-schmidt</id>
<content type="html" xml:base="http://ihadtendollars.com/interviews/katie-rose-pipkin-and-loren-schmidt.html">&lt;h4&gt;Who are you and what do you do for a living&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;k: my name is &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/katierosepipkin&quot;&gt;katie rose pipkin&lt;/a&gt;. i string together a system of odd jobs and incidental work, including; teaching, gallery sales, slinging esoterica, taking commissioned work, web development, public art projects, small grants, murals, and a studio sublet in exchange for my curatorial role at an austin-based arts space. i am a series of symbols that looks like a field of flowers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;l: i’m &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/lorenschmidt&quot;&gt;loren schmidt&lt;/a&gt;. i work on various digital art projects, including games. i do various odd jobs to help pay the bills, including contract art and programming for other folks’ projects. i also recently started a patreon, which will hopefully help me focus more on my own projects:
&lt;a href=&quot;patreon.com/vacuumflowers&quot;&gt;patreon.com/vacuumflowers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Could you briefly describe &lt;a href=&quot;http://inflorescence.city/&quot;&gt;inflorescence.city&lt;/a&gt;? What was the catalyst for the project?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;k: infloresence.city is a small journal about a city generated anew every time it is visited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;l: we started with the idea of doing something composed of a number of fragments, and the idea of visiting a city from multiple perspectives arose from that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/posts/inflorescence/inflorescence1.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;444&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/inflorescence/inflorescence1.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;How did you make it / what’s it built with?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;k: it is almost entirely built in javascript, with html5 canvas as platform for the illustrations. there are also a few programs in ruby (some work there done by the ever-talented &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/zonodonoceros&quot;&gt;@zonodonoceros&lt;/a&gt;), and a small twine game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;What were the biggest challenges for infloresence.city and how did you get around them?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;l: we wanted to make sure the project was accessible. it can be a bit disorienting to come across a wall of generated text and not know what’s going on. i think the way this piece is broken up into diverse segments helps a lot, as does the fact that it’s so visual. it’s also important that everything in the project is coming from a very personal place: people can sense that, and it makes it easier to connect and let it in. we also knew we needed to communicate the nature of the piece to people, so we were careful to present the basics whenever talking about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/posts/inflorescence/inflorescence2.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;427&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/inflorescence/inflorescence2.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;When we talked earlier, you mentioned this started as a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theverge.com/2014/11/25/7276157/nanogenmo-robot-author-novel&quot;&gt;nanogenmo&lt;/a&gt; project. What about it made you think it was something that should be worked on outside of that event?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;k: in short, we ran out of time! i don’t think it is an uncommon sentiment when working on large projects within short deadlines, but the place it was by december 1st was fairly shallow of the place we hoped to leave it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;l: that and the pile of ideas we came up with for future projects…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;k: bless scope creep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Inflorescence.city is generated anew every time the page loads. Maybe I didn’t visit it enough times, but it seems like certain parts are always the same. Are pieces hard coded? If so, how did you decide what to compose yourself and what to have generated?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;k: the pieces that are hard-coded (the news, in particular) are generated from ruby programs that “i was going to get working in the browser”. at this point i think i may offer them for a download instead? or perhaps their structure will be re-used for a slightly more elegant version of the same idea. for example, the section with the war-words to flowers (the news), really should be a web portal or browser extension. it is on my vast to-do list.
note: since i wrote this, i published that chrome extension; &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/rose-colored-window/djlhhopgmokkhnljjlkclknddoododoc/&quot;&gt;it is available for free here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/posts/inflorescence/inflorescence3.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;444&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/inflorescence/inflorescence3.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;What do you think the generated text adds to the experience for the reader? For instance, the name of the park with the gravestones, and even the city itself, vary, but a reader might only visit once and wouldn’t pick up on it. Does your ideal reader visit more than once? Is the interesting part for you the potential for what could happen?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;l: for me, the independence of the process is important. not just knowing that it will be different each time, but having a sense of the software as a creative force with its own notions and tendencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;k: i am very interested in making individual experiences or artworks for every person who chooses to engage. this iteration of this project used random seed variables to produce that effect- going forward, i am exploring ways to generate work uniquely, but not /randomly/- tracking mouse patterns, browser version, timestamp data, the world of silent information that is unique to each of us on the internet. perhaps this particularization isn’t evident to every visitor, but I hope that it becomes important to those who engage in that way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;l: for future work, i’m really interested in doing things which are location and time specific!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;I feel like I see something about algorithms having a point of view quite a bit in my Twitter feed. I feel like that is easier to unpack when I’m thinking about algorithms used in products, but I was wondering if you could talk a bit about what it means to write an algorithm for artistic purposes.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;l: i think ascribing intent to algorithms is shorthand, a way for humans to be loving and respectful within a human vocabulary. pure algorithms do, on some level, exist outside of human invention. but it’s difficult to draw a line and separate the shape contributed by the computer from that contributed by the human. there is so much crosstalk between humans and computers. our monitors are shaped to fit human eyes, our cultures are reflected in programming languages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;k: writing an algorithm to produce artworks is sort of like making ten thousand individual pieces at once. the practice of defining rulesets to make the kind of work that you wish to see is similar, but not identical to, making the artwork alone would have been. it is sort of a reversed-process; it takes a broad-scope view of the /what/ those defining characteristics are, how they fit together, what makes them compelling- as opposed to the process of finding an individual feature that moves you, and later seeing that it fits in with all of these others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;There are quite a few striking visualizations that get generated and I’m curious what it means in the afterword when you write that these are instances where the “text takes visual form”.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;l: the illustrator we used for this project is an effort at translating text into a meaningful visual form. the drawings are made by doing one to one translations of parts of the text. the letter q might mean “turn left, then go forward”&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
<summary>Who are you and what do you do for a living</summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>Jessica Lord - Sheetsee</title>
<link href="http://ihadtendollars.com/interviews/jessica-lord.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Jessica Lord - Sheetsee" />
<published>2014-12-04T00:00:00-08:00</published>
<updated>2014-12-04T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
<id>http://ihadtendollars.com/interviews/jessica-lord</id>
<content type="html" xml:base="http://ihadtendollars.com/interviews/jessica-lord.html">&lt;p&gt;I met Jessica at &lt;a href=&quot;http://tacoconf.com/&quot;&gt;Taco Conf&lt;/a&gt; when she was at Code for America, and I remember being really inspired by her work as well as the passion she had for it. One of the things I like about Jessica’s work is that you get the sense that she really cares about helping people solve problems, and goes about it in a way that gets them started on a track where they can keep improving their solutions. As you’ll see, Sheetsee lowers the barrier for visualizing data using tools people are already familiar with. Her project &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jlord/git-it&quot;&gt;Git-it&lt;/a&gt; is an application that runs in your terminal to help you learn how to use git and github.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think a good way to put it is that Jessica makes software that feels welcoming. I look at it and feel comfortable starting something new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Who are you and what do you do for a living?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/jlord&quot;&gt;Jessica Lord&lt;/a&gt; and I’m a front-end developer and designer at &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/jlord&quot;&gt;GitHub.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Can you describe &lt;a href=&quot;http://jlord.github.io/sheetsee.js/&quot;&gt;Sheetsee&lt;/a&gt; really quick?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jlord.github.io/sheetsee.js/&quot;&gt;Sheetsee.js&lt;/a&gt; is a client-side library designed to be connected to a Google Spreadsheet (using &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jsoma/tabletop&quot;&gt;Tabletop.js&lt;/a&gt;) and turning that data into maps, charts and tables—and hopefully then lowering the barrier to entry for having a simple website with visualizations and a simple database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Where did you get the idea for Sheetsee?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea for Sheetsee came &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Q76bKK229aM&quot;&gt;during my fellowship year at Code for America&lt;/a&gt;. I was working with the area I grew up in actually, Macon, Georgia, and the budget office wanted to share how they were spending some money the city would be getting through a bond referendum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d just come from 3 years in working for the City of Boston and had taken from that a desire to incorporate some of the useful web services we take for granted, like Google apps, into city government. I also believed that departments should be able to manage and update content on their websites themselves and that we could reduce the bottleneck of tasks a city IT department is asked to handle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So with that I wanted to use a Google spreadsheet as a database. It was free, didn’t need installing and it wasn’t a new interface to learn, it was a spreadsheet and people were familiar with that. I wanted to make something that was easy to set up with minimal HTML and JS knowledge and even easier to maintain by just editing cells on a spreadsheet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;What are some of your favorite uses for Sheetsee? Who has done cool things with it or used to particularly good effect?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yeah! Some libraries have used it, people have used it to crowdsource information through spreadsheets. Most of the time I don’t know when people are using Sheetsee unless they tell me. Every now and then I meet someone randomly and they say they’ve used it or even been paid to use it and that’s neat!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People have been forking some of the Sheetsee-based projects I have on GitHub and reworking them for what they want. That’s another neat thing about Sheetsee and the fact that GitHub will host website for every repository, you can fork an existing Sheetsee-based project (or any for that matter!), copy the header cells on its spreadsheet, paste them into a new spreadsheet and then edit the spreadsheet url on your fork of the project (which you can do online with GitHub, without Git or a text editor installed). Then you’ll have a website live and hosted connected to data that’s yours. I really think the fork and GitHub Pages tools combined are really powerful and put together a page, &lt;a href=&quot;http://jlord.us/fork-n-go/&quot;&gt;Fork-n-go&lt;/a&gt;, to list some examples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Is Sheetsee done? Is there anything you would like to add to it or clean up?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No way! There are lots of things I’d love to see refined or added. I try to work on it as much as I can, but I am but one person (so, pull requests welcome!). I’d like to make the sorting not just work for the alphabet, I’d like to add marker clustering to maps, it needs tests! I’d love to see more fork-n-go projects built with Sheetsee, and it needs tests! And whatever else is open in the Issues for the repository!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
<summary>I met Jessica at Taco Conf when she was at Code for America, and I remember being really inspired by her work as well as the passion she had for it. One of the things I like about Jessica’s work is that you get the sense that she really cares about helping people solve problems, and goes about it in a way that gets them started on a track where they can keep improving their solutions. As you’ll see, Sheetsee lowers the barrier for visualizing data using tools people are already familiar with. Her project Git-it is an application that runs in your terminal to help you learn how to use git and github.</summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>Amber Gordon - Femsplain</title>
<link href="http://ihadtendollars.com/interviews/amber-gordon.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Amber Gordon - Femsplain" />
<published>2014-11-13T00:00:00-08:00</published>
<updated>2014-11-13T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
<id>http://ihadtendollars.com/interviews/amber-gordon</id>
<content type="html" xml:base="http://ihadtendollars.com/interviews/amber-gordon.html">&lt;p&gt;I dislike the term “internet savvy” because it doesn’t really tell me anything – There are just so many parts of the internet and so many types of behaviors that take place on it – but if there’s anyone it’s safe to say is internet savvy, I think it would probably be Amber.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I emailed Amber these questions before the site even launched because I knew she would bring her own perspective to what a platform for women should be and knock it out of the park. I wasn’t exactly sure what to expect, but it has been great watching &lt;a href=&quot;http://femsplain.com&quot;&gt;Femsplain&lt;/a&gt; unfold over the couple of weeks. For one thing, Femsplain fits Tumblr like a glove. I really like how they reblog their writers and publish pull quotes (the type of thing typically shared on Tumblr anyway) as their own separate posts. Sometimes the line between the &lt;a href=&quot;http://femsplain.tumblr.com/&quot;&gt;Femsplain Tumblr&lt;/a&gt; and main site kind of get blurred for me a little bit, but that’s interesting too. And the topic of “firsts” is broad enough that there is a breadth of different subjects and voices represented. In less than a month a place holder landing page has turned into what feels like a vibrant community space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, Amber now&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Who are you and what do you do for a living?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/missambear&quot;&gt;Amber Gordon&lt;/a&gt;, 24 years old. Lover of coffee, content, and Internet culture. I live in a sublet apartment in Chelsea, NYC. My hobbies include discovering weird online communities, playing online games when I have time, and learning as much as I can about whatever excites me. For a living I’m a Creative Strategist at &lt;a href=&quot;http://tumblr.com&quot;&gt;Tumblr&lt;/a&gt;. It’s really a fancy title, but what it means is I ideate creative content solutions and consult top 100 brands on how best to use the Tumblr platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;What is &lt;a href=&quot;http://femsplain.com&quot;&gt;Femsplain&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://femsplain.com&quot;&gt;Femsplain&lt;/a&gt; is a publishing platform for anyone who identifies as a woman to contribute any type of content fitting the assigned month’s theme. We also encourage anyone to read and support the voices that have contributed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Did you look to other publications or writers for inspiration? I initially thought of Lady Bits when I heard about Femsplain, but it’s not really centralized; and the monthly theme and open call made me think about 24 Hour Mag, but you’ll be releasing content regularly instead of in issues.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I certainly listed out publications and writers I admired, I also listed publications I didn’t want to imitate for x and y reasons. Three of those [prior] publications were &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rookiemag.com/&quot;&gt;Rookie Mag&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://the-toast.net/&quot;&gt;The Toast&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://thehairpin.com/&quot;&gt;The Hairpin&lt;/a&gt;. More importantly, two writers who’ve inspire me and I greatly admire are &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jazzedloon&quot;&gt;Jazmine Hughes&lt;/a&gt; (Contributing Editor at The Hairpin) and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jessicakroy&quot;&gt;Jessica Roy&lt;/a&gt; (Senior Writer at New York Mag). Both are incredibly smart, funny, and just really good women, whom without knowing I’m doubtful I’d have the courage to launch &lt;a href=&quot;http://femsplain.com&quot;&gt;Femsplain&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;How did you settle on the idea of themed months?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The themed months idea came from being stumped on, funny enough, which emoji categories we wanted to have. The emojis made it through to the launch but we decided against the traditional categories so that our contributors wouldn’t feel obligated to pick a specific one to write about. We’ve also made it so that the themes are broad enough that way anyone can create something with the theme loosely in their mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;It seems like you’ve put a lot of effort into emphasizing that Femsplain is a place for any woman to be heard. The submission guidelines are quite open, even allowing for screenshots of text threads. I was wondering if you’ve struggled at all between maintaining quality and making sure people who might not normally have a chance to be heard, or aren’t as experienced writing, still get included.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far the quality of the pieces we’ve received are incredible. I honestly didn’t know what to expect from the open submissions because honestly I didn’t know if anyone would contribute. At this date we’ve filled our content calendar for the month of November, 3 pieces per day, and they’re all insanely good. They feel so authentic and meaningful, every single one of them. You can feel how real emotions went into every piece, even the ones meant to be comical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course we’ve gotten a fair amount of inquiries on sharing Tinder stories and to “maintain a quality” to the site we’ve just asked those women to still contribute but consider a different story. We don’t want to turn anyone who wants to share something away, and they understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;What do you think the biggest opportunity for Femsplain is? Like, what is the impact you’d most like to have?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My vision for &lt;a href=&quot;http://femsplain.com&quot;&gt;Femsplain&lt;/a&gt; has become harder and harder to talk about as each day passes. Every day something amazing happens that I would have never dreamed would and it’s so overwhelming. Everyone is so willing to offer their help, women and men. A great example of that is the day Femsplain launched, I was having site load issues because of the volume of people visiting the site. Someone on Twitter, who’m I hadn’t known till he tweeted at me asking if I needed help showed me how to fix the issues I was having over GChat. The other day one woman donated an unnecessarily large amount of money towards the launch party we’re having on the 21st. I have an entire volunteer staff of 17 women, editors, contributors, and one fantastic person who comes over my house every Sunday for the past few weeks to help me with anything I’m behind on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went off on a huge tangent, but really this is what my hopes are. We all come together to build a positive, supportive community that feels real. Like you mentioned, there really is a lack of visibility into what women go through everyday. If we can talk about our problems, triumphs, fears, and passions in a safe space and create thoughtful and educated conversations from them that’s a start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually I’d love to turn &lt;a href=&quot;http://femsplain.com&quot;&gt;Femsplain&lt;/a&gt; into something bigger, but right now I’m focused on building and spreading awareness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Me again. Thanks Amber! Here are a few of my favorite pieces on Femsplain right now if you’re interested, dear spirited reader.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://femsplain.com/everyone-on-tinder-is-my-boyfriend/&quot;&gt;Everyone On Tinder Is My Boyfriend&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://femsplain.com/stop-giving-marketing-agencies-credit-that-the-fangirls-deserve/&quot;&gt;Stop Giving Marketing Agencies Credit That The Fangirls Deserve&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://femsplain.com/the-lost-art-of-making-out/&quot;&gt;The Lost Art Of Making Out&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
<summary>I dislike the term “internet savvy” because it doesn’t really tell me anything – There are just so many parts of the internet and so many types of behaviors that take place on it – but if there’s anyone it’s safe to say is internet savvy, I think it would probably be Amber.</summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>David McCreath - It Might Get Personal</title>
<link href="http://ihadtendollars.com/interviews/mccreath.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="David McCreath - It Might Get Personal" />
<published>2014-10-23T00:00:00-07:00</published>
<updated>2014-10-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
<id>http://ihadtendollars.com/interviews/mccreath</id>
<content type="html" xml:base="http://ihadtendollars.com/interviews/mccreath.html">&lt;h4&gt;Who are you and what do you do for a living?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/mccreath&quot;&gt;David McCreath&lt;/a&gt; and I work on the Internet for a living. Currently that takes the shape of doing customer and technical support at &lt;a href=&quot;https://slack.com/&quot;&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt;, but I got my start as a designer, did middleware and backend for a while,  and most recently finished up eight years of doing front end development at &lt;a href=&quot;http://muledesign.com/&quot;&gt;Mule Design&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Did It Might Get Personal start as a result of Mule’s podcast network? Was it something you were working on beforehand?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea for IMGP was bubbling around for close to a year before &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.muleradio.net/&quot;&gt;Mule Radio&lt;/a&gt; got going, but the network is definitely what gave me the nudge to actually start making episodes. When we decided to commit company time to the network, it was like a bunch of kids putting on a show. Everyone had an idea for a podcast, and basically anyone who had an idea could put it on the network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;How long have you been playing music for others?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The very first public singing that I did was in the kids’ choir at my family’s church. After that there were some violin recitals and high school choir stuff. But the first time I played guitar on stage was when I was 15, accompanying my high school show choir on a medley of Beach Boys songs (think Glee, but without the dancing). I’d been taking lessons for about six months and was still playing everything with your basic cowboy chords, but it was everything I’d hoped it would be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;How do you think a song changes between when someone sings onstage versus to a single person, and where do you think performing for the podcast falls?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, the biggest obvious difference is intimacy. There are musicians who can make a performance on stage feel very intimate, but my feeling is that the way they do that is by not singing to a giant room full of people, but to someone very specific. That may be an imagined person or it may be themselves. On the other hand, when one person is singing directly to or for one other person it is by definition intimate, just like talking. Singing tends to be a more emotional expression. Not saying that it always is, but even watching someone  sing a nursery rhyme, you can see them get happier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So where does the podcast fall? I think it’s a little weird for some people, and intimate might not be the right word for it. There is an intimacy to it, but the guests don’t really sing to me. You can tell some of them are singing to someone. Sometimes I think it’s another version of themselves, like they’re both the audience and the singer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think recording in a studio might feel strange to people who’ve never been in one, and having all the microphones and lights and camera definitely makes it something other than singing in the shower or car. But the studio where we record right now is a small room, like the size of a living room maybe. Definitely not one of those giant cathedral looking studio rooms you see, and I think that helps some.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Do you have a sense of how your guests have found the experience? Are there any themes in their reactions?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ones without any real singing experience have said almost universally that it was hard to get up the nerve, but they felt glad for having done it. The more experienced singers generally seem to have a good time. There have only been a couple of episodes where the guest and I agreed that we needed a do-over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;How did you decide on the video podcast format? I don’t know a lot about the podcast scene, but it seems like video podcasts often get short shrift when it comes to podcasting apps on iOS. Some don’t support them at all. Did you worry about that when you were starting?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Videos are definitely not the most common format. I think most people think of podcasts as something you turn on while you’re doing other stuff; not something to really sit with. But that’s the opposite of what I want IMGP to be. I want people to stop what they’re doing for 5 or 10 minutes and watch the podcast. So, no, I never worried about it. I think it’s absolutely the right format for this podcast. I don’t know how many people actually do stop and watch, but that’s the goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my biggest inspirations for this podcast was NPR’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.npr.org/series/tiny-desk-concerts/&quot;&gt;Tiny Desk Concerts&lt;/a&gt;. There were two things in particular that I thought work really well. First, it’s fun to watch people sing. Sure, if it’s your favorite band doing your favorite songs, just listening to a really exciting live recording can be really fun. But if it’s one song, and it’s someone who may be inexperienced, watching just makes it better. Second, they keep it short. 15–20 minutes (some run longer, but not that often.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;I don’t think I’ve ever covered how a project is supported financially on the site before. You don’t have company sponsors – you’ve chosen to use tugboat to get support from your community. What effect, if any, do you think that has on the show?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve gotten a bit here and there. When I very first started with &lt;a href=&quot;https://tugboatyards.com/page/imgp&quot;&gt;Tugboat&lt;/a&gt;, I made a concerted effort to push it and raise some money, and I got enough to buy a new camera. It was great. But fundraising is a crapload of work. You really have to stay on top of it all the time for it to pay off. I think if I couldn’t afford to make the show on my own, I’d be more inclined to keep at it. But I’m fortunate enough to be in a position of being able to foot the bill, so I get to do exactly what I want. Any guest I want, any song I want, any skill level I want. It’s pretty great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;You were your own guest for the last episode, what was the experience of being on the other side of it like?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, I love doing my own episodes. I’ve done three of them: 10, 27, and 49. If I didn’t think people would get sick of me, I’d probably do one every session, which would make me the guest on every fourth episode or so. The main thing for me to remember is to actually think about what I’m going to say about the song before I sit down to talk. Otherwise I’ll just ramble and drift and get off topic and probably say something inappropriate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;The last post was posted at the end of September, but recorded on August 15th, and you said you were going to be taking a break and figuring out how to try some new things. Have you been on break long enough to know what some of those new things are? Can you share some of the things you’re excited to try?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last episode was actually posted on August 15. [Editor’s note: oops] I had intended to be up and running again by now, but there’s been a lot of life happening, so it’s going to be at least another month or so before we get anything up. Here are some of the things we’ll be trying in the future:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Using multiple cameras&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Doing more out-of-studio recording (like Episodes 36 and 37, which I recorded at a conference in Chicago)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Possibly recording some San Francisco’s street musicians&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Figuring out how to work with remote guests (I have a list of people from out of town who want to be on the show)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
<summary>Who are you and what do you do for a living?</summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>Jennifer Dewalt - 180 Websites in 180 Days</title>
<link href="http://ihadtendollars.com/interviews/jennifer-dewalt.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Jennifer Dewalt - 180 Websites in 180 Days" />
<published>2014-10-16T00:00:00-07:00</published>
<updated>2014-10-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
<id>http://ihadtendollars.com/interviews/jennifer-dewalt</id>
<content type="html" xml:base="http://ihadtendollars.com/interviews/jennifer-dewalt.html">&lt;h4&gt;Who are you, and what do you do for a living?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am an artist turned software developer. I taught myself to code by making &lt;a href=&quot;http://jenniferdewalt.com/&quot;&gt;180 websites in 180 days&lt;/a&gt;. I’m currently Hacker in Residence at &lt;a href=&quot;http://wit.ai&quot;&gt;Wit.ai&lt;/a&gt; where I do a lot of different things including hacking on special projects using our voice interface API.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;How did you decide you were going to make 180 sites in 180 days? How much experience coding did you have before the beginning?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I decided I wanted to learn to code, I hadn’t done any real programming before. I looked around at all of this amazing technology that’s growing around us and realized that I wasn’t satisfied with just consuming those products, I wanted to be able to build them too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I knew I wanted to do a self directed project and I started thinking about what a successful, self directed project would look like for a beginner coder. I decided I should start with small projects and build up my skill set piece by piece. I also knew I wanted to work on things that were tangible so I could track my progress and stay motivated. The 180 ideas started out a joke with a friend when I told him I was going to work on a few small websites before I tackled a full stack project. He asked how many small projects I thought I could do. We went back and forth for a bit and suddenly it sounded like a good idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;It seems like one of the biggest barriers for a project like this is generating enough ideas. How did you decide what you were going to build on any given day?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I started, I made a big list of every good, bad, crazy, half realized idea for a website I could think of. I ended up with about 70 ideas and it definitely helped frame what my definition of a website was. I started with the list but pretty quickly the project started almost driving itself. I was often inspired by the work I had done the day before. I’d come across a concept or code snippet that I hadn’t learned about yet and I’d think “That’s cool! What kind of app would use something like that?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;For projects like these I always wonder whether it’s a strict one a day process. Did you ever work in easier projects to give you time to do multi-day big things? Did you ever have to switch projects because you wouldn’t meet your deadline?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I set a strict rule of one website per day, everyday. I was averaging about 10 hours a day on the project so if I needed to find some extra time for other things (like flying to the east coast for my sister’s wedding) I had to get creative. I’d usually try to work in some easier websites or do some research the day before if I knew I was going to be short on time. I got really good at knowing how long a project would probably take and working in uncomfortable environments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite getting good and judging how long an idea would take to execute, there were definitely a number of days where things didn’t go as planned. There were a few days where I worked until 8 or 9 pm and suddenly realized I’d have to scrap what I was doing and start all over. Those days were pretty scary. Usually if I found myself in trouble it was more a matter of switching gears and reimagining what my goal for the day was. &lt;a href=&quot;http://jenniferdewalt.com/swivel/game&quot;&gt;Swivel&lt;/a&gt; is a good example of that. I had this bananas idea for a really complicated chain reaction game that turns out was really tough to code. I had to rewrite the chain reaction logic 3 or 4 times before I got it all worked out. By the time I got it working it was too late to add in the game mechanics. In a sense it’s a fail because I didn’t finish what I originally set out to do, but I’m still really proud of Swivel and I think it’s a neat website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;What do you think makes the one-a-day method so compelling, as opposed to say five a week?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working on a learning project every single day means there is not a lot knowledge leakage. You’re constantly present with what you’re working on and it is always on your mind. The structure also makes it easier to stay motivated, I think. There’s no room to question whether you’re going to work on your project today. Whether you’re tired, confused, frustrated, sick, hungover or whatever there are no excuses. It’s kind of freeing in a weird, masochistic sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;What was the most popular site you built?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s hard to say actually! A handful of sites like the &lt;a href=&quot;http://jenniferdewalt.com/hipster_quiz.html&quot;&gt;Hipster Quiz&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://jenniferdewalt.com/etch_a_sketch.html&quot;&gt;Etch-a-Sketch&lt;/a&gt; have ended up in various subreddits which I think is pretty cool and very flattering. Different people gravitate toward different sites. My data nerd friends love &lt;a href=&quot;http://jenniferdewalt.com/elevation/page&quot;&gt;Elevations&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;http://jenniferdewalt.com/node/how_were_feeling&quot;&gt;How We’re Feeling&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://jenniferdewalt.com/splodin_bacon/page&quot;&gt;Splodin Bacon&lt;/a&gt; get the a lot of universal appreciation. And people have made over 16,000 Little Dudes using &lt;a href=&quot;http://jenniferdewalt.com/make_a_dude/dudes&quot;&gt;Make a Dude&lt;/a&gt; which I find mind blowingly awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;What is your favorite, or the most meaningful one to you?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jenniferdewalt.com/splodin_bacon/page&quot;&gt;Splodin Bacon&lt;/a&gt; holds a special place in my heart because it’s the website I made the day my project went viral and I was totally freaking out when I made it. I’m also really fond of &lt;a href=&quot;http://jenniferdewalt.com/electro_bounce/page&quot;&gt;Electro Bounce&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://jenniferdewalt.com/audio_garden/gardens&quot;&gt;Audio Garden&lt;/a&gt;. I feel like I was really hitting my stride at that point, combining lots of different coding concepts with my art background. I also really love the data visualization apps like &lt;a href=&quot;http://jenniferdewalt.com/elevation/page&quot;&gt;Elevations&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://jenniferdewalt.com/node/how_were_feeling&quot;&gt;How We’re Feeling&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;What were the biggest lessons you learned over the course of the project? Were there any major surprises?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My biggest takeaway was letting go of my fear of making mistakes. Putting all of my work out in public was really scary at first. But as a coder you are constantly making mistakes. Your code is always broken until it’s not (and even then it’s usually still broken). Being ok with that is the only way not to be paralyzed by fear and keep making progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A big surprise for me was how much I love data! I’ve never been a math or statistics nerd and if you told me 3 years ago I was going to develop a passion for API’s I would have thought you were bonkers. I’ve always known that I’m fundamentally interested in the communication power of technology but I also find it totally fascinating take raw information and turn it into something digestible. In retrospect I guess it makes sense but I may never have discovered that had I not gone through the 180 Websites project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;A lot of the sites seem to retain the last session. For example, &lt;a href=&quot;http://jenniferdewalt.com/node/talking_dude&quot;&gt;Talking Dude&lt;/a&gt; displays the text that was last put in by someone, and most of the drawing ones I saw have past doodles that can be wiped or built on top of. Is that a conscious decision on your part because you think that interaction is interesting, or was it the easiest way for you to build them?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I set out to do 180 Websites, my goal was to be able to make full scale, dynamic, interactive web apps. Early in the project I was only able to have a one way conversation. I could communicate a message to someone by creating a site that they could play with but they couldn’t say anything to me or anyone else. When I started working with Rails (day 69) I was finally able to let people communicate with each other through my sites. I immediately starting thinking about what kind of websites would let people leave a mark that others could find. That is what inspired sites like Make a Dude and Portrait.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the project moved along I started thinking more about how people could use my websites to communicate with other people more directly. I ended up making several sites that let you create something and then either download the product to your computer or save it with a special URL that you can pass along to anyone. That is the idea behind sites like &lt;a href=&quot;http://jenniferdewalt.com/forest/page&quot;&gt;Trees for the Forest&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://jenniferdewalt.com/audio_garden/gardens&quot;&gt;Audio Garden&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the end of the project I was really excited to try out some real time communication apps using Node.js. &lt;a href=&quot;http://jenniferdewalt.com/node/all_draw&quot;&gt;All Draw&lt;/a&gt; is a real time collaborative drawing app which I think embodies a lot of what I love about the internet. The web gives us the ability to creatively communicate with anyone around the world. That is pretty powerful stuff when you think about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;This project concluded over a year ago, how have things been going since then? Do you still quickly build sites for fun?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Life’s been pretty awesome since I finished 180 Websites. After the project I decided to work on a full scale website called &lt;a href=&quot;http://yumhacker.com/&quot;&gt;YumHacker&lt;/a&gt; to get the real full stack engineering experience. I coded the whole thing myself and even went out and did some biz dev and SEO work on it to explore the full product development cycle. I learned a ton about both coding and how to grow a product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In August I joined &lt;a href=&quot;http://wit.ai&quot;&gt;Wit.ai&lt;/a&gt; as Hacker in Residence. We have an API that makes it super easy for developers to add voice interfaces to their apps. It’s wicked cool stuff. A big part of my job is to make interesting hacks using our API to explore possible use cases for Wit and to help other developers integrate Wit into their projects. Between the making cool stuff part and our intense focus on UX and communication, it’s basically the perfect job for me.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
<summary>Who are you, and what do you do for a living?</summary>
</entry>
</feed>
